The breakout attempt failed miserably; of six prisoners, only four still lived to be recaptured. These four now knelt at the entrance to the prison, flanked on both sides by guards. The Marshal paced back and forth before them, looking most displeased.

“Who incited the breakout?” the Marshal asked the prisoner at the end of the line.

The first near-escapee had been with the militia a decade fewer than the oldest surviving prisoner, yet decades longer than the other two. A practical man, he had endured countless skirmishes through careful consideration of when to retreat. 

“Shiv started it, and the others followed. To be honest, I was against the escape plan from the start. I begged them not to make trouble, but they forced me to go along. Just ask anyone here—if they don’t say the same, they are lying!”

“A man without a spine does not need his head either,” replied the Marshal. The head was promptly removed.

Next in line was a senior among the ranks of the village militia. Brave in character, though silver of hair, age had tempered the passion of his youth. He knew what needed to be said.

“I am the one called Shiv. I led the escape. The others are blameless. Let them free. Punish only me,” said he.

“Noble intent ought not cater to the whims of the unworthy,” said the Marshal. The executioner was called again.

The Marshal turned to the third prisoner. “You look like a bright young fellow. Who is responsible for the breakout?”

This one had untied his bindings while the first two were questioned. Outraged by the direct address, he grabbed a sword from the nearest guard and leveled it at the unarmed Marshal. 

“It clearly doesn’t matter what I say. You’d just have me killed.”

“Correct,” said the Marshal. He snapped his fingers, and the insolent escapee burst into flames.

The fourth and final prisoner was wounded, as he had been since their initial capture. When he spoke, his voice was weak. "How... how...?"

“‘How could you?’” the Marshal predicted.

“No.” The fourth escapee looked up from the charred pile of his former colleague. Hunger glistened fever-bright in his eyes. "How can I?"

To the astonishment of all the prison guards, the Marshal spared this one.
