Reeds rustle with the hollow echoes of a long-lost springtime, and the drifter breathes in time with their soft melancholy. The autumn marshes are musty with the stench of decay, though summer has only ceased a mere two months ago. The cycles of the world are wrought with sadness, for every bright sunrise and bold new life fades to darkness and dust before the drifter’s eyes. It is a bleak existence, watching the strong and weak alike crumble with the passing of time until all that remains is the solitary candle of one’s own making.

The drifter beheld a sunrise, once, whose rising brilliance seemed to permeate all the world with a glory undying. Some hailed this beacon a hero, praising the one who defied the pettiness and fragile mortality of the masses to question a status quo that no one else dared think upon, while others condemned the peerless commoner for the darkest of villainies: the crime of rising above one’s predestined path. The drifter has always been a steadfast member of the former group: the first herald of a would-be revolutionary, the most devout member of the movement, and the last remaining devotee after the revolution had itself been revolted against. 

To the long-ago promise of change, the drifter had sworn loyalty—a knee bent in respect unparalleled, and a head bowed in awe never before known. No more devoted follower of the star’s cause existed, and no darker deed had been done than by the drifter’s honored duty. The sunrise had blazed as no light the drifter could recall before or since, and for its glad purpose the drifter never hesitated to sacrifice all. 

As the pure vision of a crimson dawn relented to the golden heat of midday, the drifter had fought through shadow and steel for the flag of a crown that must never fall. Yet fall the crown had, as ever the days must end and the seasons turn. The star that had inspired a nation under its brilliance fell to the inevitable, and anarchy took hold where the drifter’s ilk had once imposed order supreme. No sunrise ever shone with more splendor than the original, though the drifter tore the world apart seeking one; no pitiful bonfire could compete with the glory of a star now extinguished by a fate foreseen. 

A beloved nation, united by the sole command of its fallen leader, dissipated as smoke from countless pyres. Fire consumed the nation as the drifter defended memory from the faithless; when crown and country parted ways, the drifter fought for one and lost both. Then came the winter of ash and despair. A new crown ascended to the golden throne, yet the drifter would hear no command that could reign in his inferno, for trembling arms had clutched the somber crimson crown that neither love nor rage could revive. Helplessness was not a sensation known before that day, nor one that the drifter ever cared to experience again.

A little bird trills within the reeds. Whether the sound is of delight or warning does not matter; such sweet music recalls a soft delight from the golden days before the fall, a weary smile from the chaos during those final battles. Fondly, the drifter conjures the face of a brother by oath, equal and opposite, an opponent now lost to time—not defeated, never deceased; merely lost. For long years, the drifter searched the living and the dead for that equivalent countenance, the noblest of knights, yet no sign of the brother ever emerged. Like the pale green fields of spring or the fair blue skies of summer, the brother was lost but never gone; the drifter held hope, fragile as a blade of glass, that when the seasons turned, that lost artefact of a previous lifetime would return once more.

“Lost,” the drifter murmurs, heart sinking at the mournful chime of the word. It feels like the lie of a child who cannot face the truth, yet the drifter knows not what other truth might exist. Childhood had come and gone long ago, along with any inclinations toward self-deception. The drifter closes eyes that, even now, burn with the embers of power with neither master to serve, nor charge to protect. 

The drifter knows this brother by no other name. If ever drifter or kin had possessed such, time has stolen it from living memory. Little enough remains of that treasured memory: a smile, not a face; a whisper of the wind and water, not a name or voice; a ghost forever sought, neither found nor forsaken. Through long years has the drifter quested for the lost brother, facing countless cycles of the seasons in unending travels across countries far and wide, and for longer still do all efforts return nothing save weariness and failure. To a king of old the drifter had sworn loyalty with blade and fiery prowess unmatched in the land, and to a crown of new the drifter had spat in open defiance of false command, yet from the lost equal whose life had shone like a mirror through every night, no power of the drifter could upturn even a passing trace. 

The pool at the drifter’s feet turns to a rift of liquid shadow in the dusk. It is a void like the endless depths of the black sky above, cavernous and cruel. There is no sun here.

Night looms heavy upon the marsh, crushing color to the tasteless grey of ink and the ocean depths. The drifter can stand the lifeless dark no more. A pouch is tossed to the ground, and the marsh erupts in gold. Light embraces every reed, lunging for the sky with fingers red as the dawn. Birds cry their sweetest song once more, and then no more. The drifter closes tired eyes to the springtime within that music, but never does the darkness lift. 

Fair and bright the fire may be, yet still it is no match for the drifter’s fallen star.

