The fisherman’s assistant lounged against a throne of barnacle-encrusted rock, peering into the depths of the ocean. An equally deep puzzlement was etched across the few surfaces of his face that could be seen beneath a cloud of overgrown auburn scruff. His voice crackled like wet stones tossed upon a bonfire. 

“The villagers say that the tides brought me from danger to friendly nets. Neither they nor I know what form of danger might have set me adrift in the first place.” 

The fisherman’s assistant waved a calloused hand at the young man perched on the neighboring rock. This young fellow had seen and done more in his lifetime than most who had survived to a wise old age, but recent years had taught him caution. He tensed, ready to flee at the slightest sign of hostility from his companion. However, the fisherman’s assistant did not appear concerned with anything more than the distant blue line of the melded sea and sky.

“Consider yourself fortunate, lad. You still remember your youth. Perhaps, when you grow as old as I am, you too shall forget... no, no, I jest. Fear not, lad! Nothing is truly lost in this world. One day, I will rediscover those memories that I have misplaced.”

‘Yes, and you will remember that I am not on your side. You will know that your power is matched by only one, and that one is not me; I defeated you by sheer luck. Then, you shall call upon your flames, and I will be toast. Again, as it ever was,’ the young man silently mused to himself. It was not a pleasant line of thought. He pressed a gloved hand to the padded inner edge of the opposite forearm, where steel lay concealed under a dark sleeve. The sleek lines of cool metal comforted his nerves. 

“One day,” the young man echoed aloud. He choked out a laugh that any other villager might have found agreeable. The sound was enough to tear his companion’s sunset-red gaze from the horizon.

“And you will be there to see it,” the fisherman’s assistant said. His eyes crinkled with well-intentioned fondness above the fuzzy curve that might have been a grin. The young man returned the smile, but his fingers dug into the charcoal cloth at his wrist.

“I will be there,” the man promised. Steel-grey eyes slid shut. ‘May this trial be our last.’