Today, tomorrow... a thousand tomorrows
Though you must forget, I never shall.
My purpose, my duty, my fell sorrows
I will remember when you are no more.

My blade is steel; your eyes are fire.
Long ago, destiny foretold this day
When the peace would split before our ire
But I will see that your embers never fade.

You were born to rise in the light;
Ever alike we were: you, bold as the sun,
And I, your shadow, forged to order the night—
Two champions of the same cause.

In the end, you and I are two halves of one,
Duty-bound and pledged to star and void,
Yet your duty is over, and mine is done.
Our work at an end, you depart with a final farewell.
