The fisherman’s assistant lounges against a majestic spur of granite. His scruffy face is upturned to the bite of the coastal wind, and the dipping sun lights his unkempt hair aglow like a forest canopy in mid-autumn. Murky water laps fondly at his knees, etching black streaks of mud into the uneven hems of his trousers. One of his arms is propped against a bucket overflowing with fresh oysters. The other rests in a patch of moss flowing from a crevice. The fisherman’s assistant has the look of a man who had seen twenty thousand sunsets, yet who desires nothing more of the world than to bask in the golden light of just one more splendid afternoon.

“Well,” muses the fisherman, whose personal bucket of oysters is only half filled, “not on my watch.”

The fisherman, called Fisher in both name and trade, considers himself to be a very sensible person. Therefore, before following his first instinct—namely, abandoning his own work to laze about besides the assistant—he assesses the situation from a rational perspective. If a fisherman’s assistant has time to lounge around on the rocks, whereas the fisherman himself is still doing honest work under the sun, then naturally the assistant wants for more tasks. Naturally. 

The fisherman prods his assistant with a stick, saying, “Up you get, Snapper.” 

Snapper blinks at Fisher with the same expression of surprise that his namesake might have employed after getting caught in a net. The assistant’s scruffy face splits into a sheepish smile, abruptly reminding Fisher of the time when a half-drowned person appeared in the deep-water nets where only fish ought to have turned up. Snapper had been a surprise then, but never since. He rises to this newest task with the unwavering obedience and dedication that would put even the most patient of village laborers to shame. 

Another day slips into the past without consequence.

