The shadow is helpless as the world burns. The battle had been an even match, sword and speed against sword and muscle, before the enemy unleashed wings of light and fire across everything. After an ill-advised attempt to block a flying object, the shadow’s weapon has become a puddle on the ground—the bright iron, forged by the most expensive smiths in the land, had melted in an instant. The shadow crawls through a pool of crimson on unsteady hands and knees, choked by the unbearable heat that has claimed countless lives. A gash on his left flank throbs with every labored breath. He wonders how he could ever have thought it possible to challenge the wayward master of flame.

Orange veils shift, and the madman himself appears as though conjured from the essence of fire. Air shimmers with heat haze around a head haloed in auburn and smoke. The drifter’s brow is creased with infinite sorrow. He sheathes an undecorated sword—its steel, the shadow notices, is undamaged by the heat that had melted the shadow’s own weapon. 

“You are not my true enemy.” The madman’s voice is the crackle of wet stones dropped into a campfire, sharp and volatile and broken.

Within those words, the shadow reads a plea, one that he could answer but must not. He meets that vermillion gaze, fearless as only a dead man can be before such an immensely overpowered executioner.

“The Marshal of the East is dead. You struck him down.”

The shadow expects retaliation: a roar of rage, a red-hot sword to the gut, wings of pure energy and willpower unfurling to banish every trace of wispy silver cloud from the sky. He does not expect the madman to smile sadly.

“So I did. We were bound by oath.” Flames pour from the drifter’s gauntlet, striking the elegant arch of the longbow slung across his back. Gold leaps along the lines of the black metal, drawing a streak of diagonal light across the drifter’s torso. The shadow waits for a bolt of fire to impale his weakened body, but the drifter only sighs and pats out the flames on his cloak. The bowstring extinguishes into coils of smoke. 

“Why have you come?”

The shadow draws an ancient square of parchment from his cloak, wincing as the motion tugs at the wound across his side. Scalded hands leave red prints on the beige surface. He does not say, “Slaying the Marshal of the West would have brought me wealth and fame beyond compare.” Nor does he say, “The people cry for someone to stop your madness, and I am the only one left who was trained to match your sword.” Both are true enough, although swordplay had not helped in the least against the drifter’s fire. The shadow presses one hand against the gash in his side, and he offers the expired bounty poster with the other. 

“The queen... sent me.”

The drifter skims past the list of crimes, the sketch of a generic face with flames in place of hair, and the impressive sum of gold that the treasury had once offered for his head. He traces the wax impression of the royal seal with pensive fingers. Long seconds pass; the shadow sways with exhaustion, but he refuses to collapse. As the madman contemplates the partly melted seal, the hint of a smile fades into a careful blankness. 

“I am bound by oath,” the madman says at last. He produces a metal canteen from his belt and splashes a white, foamy fluid on the nearest flames. The inferno thrashes and hisses, but ultimately all fire must quail before its master’s command, and the merciless heat retreats. No life remains within sight, save for the drifting madman and the injured hunter. Their crimson and midnight cloaks, respectively stained with soot and blood, are the only splashes of color between the ashen field and silver sky. 

The drifter extends a hand, and the shadow takes it. He wants to live. 

