Morning confirms your fate foretold:
You were wrong and I was right.
If you only had been told,
My severed head would crown an iron pike,
While you might still live to grow old.
 
To keep the peace, I blinded you to this threat;
My honesty would have served you better.
I held my tongue. Quiet. Dutiful. Your mind was set.
Loyally, I obeyed your final folly to the letter—
Never had a simple soldier known more regret.
 
It was not I who revealed your policy absurd:
My brothers defied your mistaken command—
Such betrayal I could never muster! By your word,
I took their voices. Had I helped you understand,
I would lie among my kin, your survival my only reward.
 
Crimson stains the court, burns upon my knife;
If only the respect I hold for you
Were less than the value of your life,
Revolution need not have proven my doubts true,
Claiming your kingdom in murderous strife.
 
Once, the ungrateful called for your demise.
Dawn shines over the realm: your enemies are naught.
Victory is mine! Bitter solace. Grave prize.
To serve your waning wisdom was all I sought—
With your last feeble breath, my lifelong purpose dies.
