You named my creations monstrous,
And swore me your one true enemy,
Bound in opposition, ‘til one day
Your wish came true.

Little shadow, so forgetful,
Confusing fantasy with what is true,
How could you not remember?—
My greatest creation was you.

Murder in your eyes, I am proud to behold;
Never was there one so fair,
As you who pronounce my judgement,
My child, now grown high and cruel as I.

If I must die, that your legacy may begin,
Then go on—may you live forever: 
Your legacy is my own,
Though you know it not.
