You were light and I was darkness 
You were gone and I was there 
And as the world faded to shadow 
I felt everything was wrong 

It wasn't natural, it wasn't right 
I tried to forget, but nothing was alright 
The world was so dim without your light 
My darkness where it was once bright

I wanted to fix it, but I didn't know how 
Then finally I decided—it didn't matter 
How I went about doing it 
So long as the skies brightened again 

I lit a match and forsook my night
Strode forward, as always your knight 
Torch in hand, I set the world alight
So fair, so far, yet no match for your light

Now all blazes, far as the eye can see
But still it's not what you once were 
Nothing else could compare to your star
Nothing now, save my twinkling memory