Endless tales, countless heroes,
Each one fails in fading sorrows.

I am the cloud, ever present, ever passing;
I am the mourning star, everlasting;
I am the shadow of a forgotten sun;
I am the ash left when the fire’s course is run.

Nameless, I wander through the ages,
Untouched by the common world’s rages;
A past I remember, that all alive have forgotten: 
I came from nothing, and to nothing I am beholden.

To love the lives that must end in losses,
Through eons of betrayal and double-crosses
Could turn a weaker heart to stone,
Yet still I weep for those who will not atone.

I am but a hermit whose conscience
Will permit no injustice.
