When the sage descends from the mountain to visit a humble village by the shore, word of his arrival spreads faster than wildfire. There is not a man, woman, or child in the village proper who does not know of the sage’s arrival.

Naturally, the fisherman’s assistant finds out two days later, and only then because he spots a new face in town. Snapper was normally content to spend his days working on the coast. However, Fisher had needed an extra pair of hands to sell fish in the market while he and his wife went to mingle with the proper villagers—those individuals, that is, who in fact lived inside the vaguely defined village border, rather than in a cottage within shouting distance of said border. Since Snapper is not one to refuse a task, this is the first afternoon that he has spent in the village itself for months.

Business is slow today. Words float in from the vegetable vendor, who has leaned over to hiss at the baker in the stall opposite Snapper: “Look there—the sage!” Snapper cranes his neck to see: a stranger in a mossy green, grass-stained travel cloak is picking his way down the street. The sage pauses to paw through a display of fruits, exchanges one greenish copper coin for a parcel of flatbread, and wanders over to inspect the latest batch of fish. 

“Well met, Mountain Sage of the East,” Snapper greets. 

The sage tenses. “My mountain is north of here, actually.” 

Piercing verdant eyes meet vermillion ones in an identical face. Another street vendor might have recoiled from the unexpected scrutiny, but retreat is a concept that Snapper has never grasped. He simply frowns at the mistake. 

“North? But I could have sworn...” the thought fades from Snapper’s mind. “Right, sorry about that, good sir. Don’t know what I was thinking. Obviously it can’t be east—the ocean’s to the east and all.”

After a moment that stretches on for hours, the suspicious lines of the sage’s face soften into a wry smile. 

“Well met, Fisherman’s Assistant... of the West. How much for this fine trout?”

Snapper quotes a price, and the satisfied customer wanders off. Fisher will be pleased; the sage had paid the full amount without even attempting to negotiate. Snapper absently marks the transaction in the sales log, humming to himself. Wisps of cloud sprawl across the blue sky, scattering the sunlight into a diffuse silver glow. Today is a splendid day, just like all of the days that Snapper can remember. 

