After every fire, there is ash, plain and grey as a winter wasteland under the weak rays of a new dawn. The marshes are cold and still when the shadow arrives, a hunter in sable passing over the parched, colorless mud to inspect the crumbled remnants of plant life. Feet wrapped in mud-caked midnight cloth brush the ground, their light step evoking no sound from the hardened silt. The shadow raises dark fingers to the still-smoking shell of a reed. The white stalk crumbles into dust at the touch. Death has visited the peaceful countryside this night, yet the culprit is already long gone. 

For years, the shadow has tracked this quarry across the barren deserts and charred forests that scar a once-prosperous nation. It has been twelve months since the shadow first set eyes upon the bounty offered on a certain madman’s head; ten, since the crown redirected most of the gold from that bounty toward more patriotic ends. The shadow last spoke with a living person five months ago; oftentimes, standing in the wake of the latest inferno, the shadow wonders whether he will encounter one again before the day he perishes. Many have called him mad in his own right for pursuing this hopeless quest.

No matter how many clues the shadow investigates, his efforts turn up nothing save silence: no great warrior of times past, nor an aged traitor to king and country, nor even a trace of the fire-toting sorcerer that innocent townsfolk spoke of in fearful whispers. There is only a lifeless wake of stone and dust. Bounties vanish like whims in the wind, yet the shadow pursues his elusive quarry without promise of rest or reward, turning up naught but ash upon whitened meadows, clouds of smoke looming upon the horizon, and exaggerated tales of a madman with unequaled power. 

A flash of white between grey powder and black mud catches the shadow’s gaze. Steady hands brush the dust away, revealing the hidden jewel: pale, delicate twigs of a ribcage, white against the black cloth of his gloves. The tips of feathers fan out from the wing-bones of a bird that perished in the blaze. Two gaping holes stare accusingly out of a skull no larger than the shadow’s thumb. The shadow sees himself in these bones: he, who in more peaceful days drew blade against the madman, was soundly defeated, and yet lived on by unprecedented luck; he, who hunts the one who taught him to hunt.

With swift strokes, the shadow scoops a small patch of the dusty grey earth aside and settles the miniature skeleton within its makeshift nest. The motion is one the shadow has repeated countless times. By now, acknowledging those dead to the fugitive’s fires is habit alone: a trail of buried crumbs for anyone who might care to trace the shadow’s path; a meaningless tally. 

Perhaps it always has been. 

