A wizened husk of a traveler arrived at the village tavern in the dead of night. Rags formed a midnight blue cloak about his shoulders. Sunken eyes were heavy with the shadow of countless memories, or perhaps just the shadow of dehydration. A horde of locals gathered around him, tugging at his sleeves.

“A tale,” one of the townsfolk begged. “Surely you have seen much. Tell us of your travels, oh wise adventurer.”

“Very well,” the soon-to-be storyteller said. “For food and drink, I shall regale you with a lifetime’s worth of tales.”

The audience was eager, and the requested sustenance arrived promptly. The storyteller began to speak in a rich timbre.

“I know much of the Silver Militia. Their tale is old and unpleasant, but there is a happy ending. Few now still remember those noble warriors who fought to protect the common folk. Perhaps you have not heard of them. No matter; I shall speak of their legacy tonight.”

Embers glowed dimly in the hearth, casting warm light across the storyteller’s weary figure. His garb was grey and his face tired, yet his voice rang with the strength and gravity of countless memories. 

"The order of the Silver Militia once fought for justice in a time before the King reigned supreme. They were few in number, but each was valiant and strong of heart. They protected the farmlands and traders from bandits. Where they walked, the good people rejoiced. The villages they passed were peaceful and prosperous, for the Militia always fought crime and toppled the corrupt. Their selfless deeds were known through the land, and many praised their acts of heroism."

The storyteller's voice dipped in sadness.

"On the twelfth day of the third year of the Sun King’s reign, tragedy struck. One among their order betrayed them all. Driven by the call of power, he slew his most faithful comrades in an unprecedented rage. Those he had once called brothers drew their blades to stop him, yet none could match his might in the fields or streets. He struck down the bravest of them with a single swing of his sword. More tried to fight, but they too were slaughtered. Those who did not fall at once tried to flee.” 

The storyteller’s head bowed, casting shadows across the weary lines in his skin.

“They did not get far. The betrayer tracked the cowards through the villages and towns that he had once defended, defeating each in turn. The lucky ones went quickly; three were surprised by a knife to the back, while two others fell victim to the dreamless sleep from which no man can wake. The bodies of four more were never found. As for the rest of the Silver Militia... some say their screams lasted for days, silenced only when their voices failed. Their friends, their families, anyone who helped them—all fell before his blade.” 

One of the audience shivered. The storyteller’s voice became rough.

“The betrayer came by night and left only corpses in his wake. Even the dead could not escape his wrath, for he tore out their entrails to feed the birds. Over two hundred carcasses still mark his trail, slowly rotting away with no one to bury them or mourn their passage. Not one who crossed his path was spared, innocent or guilty alike. He did not care who they were. They cursed him out of fear, and in that fear he saw weakness. Their elimination was all the reward he sought.” 

The storyteller paused. 

“They say he stalks the land to this day, lost in the thrill of the hunt."

The storyteller lapsed into a grave silence again, but the audience dared not interrupt him yet. They had been promised a happy ending to the story, and they patiently awaited the heroic twist that would surely come next. 

"Now... now, but one of the Silver Militia remains."

The storyteller regarded the assorted citizens with solemn eyes.

"I am the last."

Silence reigned for a long, stunned moment. The audience was, indeed, not disappointed. Far from it, in fact. Dozens of round faces brightened with awe, regarding the storyteller in a new light. The village lads and unsatisfied farm hands who aspired to exciting adventures in the wide world now looked upon him as a fantasy brought to life. Here was an opportunity most had only dreamed of: the chance for one used to a mundane, everyday life to hear the wisdom of an emissary from the realm of myths and fables. 

"You… no way. Really?” One young man dared inch closer, searching for more information about the heroes of times long past. His words were thick with reverence. “Tell us more of your journeys, your battles, and your triumphs! The Silver Militia of old is the stuff of stories, and you… the last… why, you're legend personified!" 

“Idle flattery merits no reward,” the storyteller gently chided. “You know not of what you speak.”

“Hold on. That means you're in danger," another member of the audience gasped, putting two and two together to create a bloody picture. The lad shuddered with despair at the thought of losing a venerable mentor figure before his own heroic endeavors could begin. He thought quickly for a way to break the news of his dreadful revelation. “The betrayer could be coming for you as we speak! We have to get you to safety—"

The storyteller’s mouth curved upward. The audience fell still, transfixed. 

"You misunderstand. I am truly the last." 

The storyteller straightened. Orange flames flashed upon hardened eyes, setting them alight with vicious promise. Cold steel glinted from the depths of his cloak.

"I am the betrayer."

